Guide to the Henry Geldzahler Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- December 1999 Acquisition, circa 1945-1996; 1; 39.04; (43 boxes)
  - Unsorted materials (Box 12, Folder 8.1)
    1) Envelope from Yale with 6 B&W photos of artwork; 3 by Frank Stella, 3 by Ellsworth Kelly. Gifts to Yale U. by Geldzahler; 2) December 1987 Opera magazine.(?); 3) Fed. Ex. envelope with color photos from Dale Chihuly. Five Polaroids of glass works, 2 photos of Geldzahler and DC. 4) Ektachrome slide sheet of sculptures by Edward Avadesian, 1976; 5) July 12, 1976 People magazine, page 70, photo of Geldzahler with Eliz Taylor and Jacqueline Onassis; 6) 16 page, orig typescript, essay by Geldzahler, "How NY Became a World Art Capital." with extensive edits in pencil and ink by Geldzahler; 7) 9 pages handwritten on legal paper, Henry's notes on "Sense of Place" lecture delivered at Tulane U. circa 1983. 8) Anonymous "Naked Sailor" Valentine card, 25 January 1983; 9) Michael Hurson, 4 B&W photos of "Empty Room" sculpture of Geldzahler's apartment (1972-3), and MCA Chicago show invite, 11 November 1973, inscribed by MH; 10) 1982 Nonesuch "Catalogue Complete".
  - Photographs, 2 (Box 12, Folder 8.2)
    1) B&W Henry on couch, model for Hockney ptg. Photo by DH; 2) B&W Henry's profile. circa 1968 Met Museum publicity photo; 3) B&W Henry and female friend photo by Phillips/Schwab, 1985; 4) B&W Henry seated photo by Mark Rudkin; 5) B&W Henry dining photo, 1980 by Helaine Messer; 6) B&W early 1960's Henry at an opening photo by William Claxton. Large group including Irving Blum, in front of combine ptg (Kaprow?); 7) B&W Henry with friends photo by Bill Cunningham; 8) B&W Henry, James Wood, Ellsworth Kelly, 1970; 9) B&W Henry standing looking out window photo by Waintrob-Budd. ea. 1960s; 10) B&W Henry laughing with Rauchenberg and Larry Rivers, photo by Edward Oleska; 11) Small color Agfa print, Henry and Andy Warhol in tuxedos photo by ?; 12) Small B&W Henry with Jules Olitski, 1968; 13) B&W Henry looking under viewer in darkroom, year/photo by ? 14) Henry with John McKendry, 1968 photo by V. Kriz; 15) B&W Henry, 1977 Denison Univ. photo by ? 16) B&W Henry speaking Denison U. silhouette of head; 17) Color Polaroid of Hockney drawing of Henry on litho stone, circa 1976 by DH; 18) B&W people viewing Hockney ptg. of Henry photo by John Lefebre; 19) B&W close up of Henry photo by Warman for NY Herald Trib, circa 1963; 20) Polaroid picture postcard from Sidney B. Felsen; 21) Color Henry photo by A. Shino, 14 February 1970; 22) Envelope with passport photos for Budapest with Frank Stella, two original 2 1/4 x 3 1/4" negatives of FS, Oct 1968; 23) B&W Leica Henry with cigar, Paris, 1972. Photo by Hans Hartung; 24) B&W Henry with Hans Hartung, Paris, 1972; 25) B&W Henry, James Wood, E. Kelly, 1970, Met; 26) B&W blurry close-up Henry, Paris, 1972; 27) B&W Henry with art installers, 1969 photo by R. Everett; 28) Small B&W Henry at Carnegie Int., Petersburgh, 1967; 29) B&W Henry playing with hair photo by Warman, NY Herald Tribune; 30) B&W Henry photo by Warman, NY Herald Tribune; 31) Color Henry with black pussy in kitchen, year/photo by ?; 32) Envelope with 2 color slides, Henry with Dick Smith's baby, 1966; 33) Color Henry and Dick Bellamy, East Hampton summer, 1968; 34) Passport page with B&W photo, 1965; 35) B&W Henry on phone, 1967; 36) B&W Henry with Frank Crowther, 1969 photo by Waintrob-Budd; 37) B&W Henry with Charles "Spinky" Alston, 1969 photo by Waintrob-Budd; 38) B&W Henry with John McKendry, 1968 photo by V. Kriz; 39) B&W Henry and Chris Scott at J. Rosenquist studio, East Hampton, 1968; 40) B&W Henry at Jewish Museum opening, 1968, with Chris Scott and Robert Irwin; 41) B&W Henry being photographed by Bruce Davidson, January 1968; 42) Envelope with photos of Henry by Andy Warhol, 1962 35mm contact prints: 3 of Geldzahler, 3 of AW, 1 unidentified woman, probably Julia Warhola; 43) B&W Henry at Metropolitan in front of Gottlieb ptg, photo by Jim Delihas; 44) B&W Henry, December 1967; 45) Small color Henry with Sidney Lewis at his home, 1973; 46) Clipping from Women's Wear Daily, 19 August 1975 of Hockney and Henry; 47) B&W Henry on the phone in front of Stella stripe ptg, photo by Paul Hyman; 48) B&W Henry reading photo by Paul Hyman; 49) B&W Henry hand on mouth photo by Paul Hyman; 50) B&W Henry on photo by Paul Hyman; 51) B&W Henry photo by Paul Hyman; 52) B&W Henry and Marty Edelheit, circa 1967, Hamptons (?); 53) B&W Henry lecturing at Museum of Natural History, 1966; 54) B&W Henry posing with sculpture photo by Sidney Waintrob; 55) B&W Henry photo by Waintrob; 56) B&W Henry with cowboy hat photo by Syeus Mottel.
  - Correspondence, 1961-1983 (Box 12, Folder 8.3)
    1) 1964 cut-out postcard mail art from Martial Raysse, France; 2) 2 page letter autograph in ink from Jess, SF, 20 April 1983; 3) B&W postcard from Ellsworth Kelly, 1965; 4) Happy New Year note on card from David Band; 5) Card from Aggie Gund, 14 March 1988; 6) Brief letter from Alanna Heiss, director of PS1., 12 September 1984; 7) Postcard from Larry Poons, 18 February 1965; 8) Postcard from Ad Reinhardt, 7 June 1965; 9) Letter from Larry Rivers, Madrid circa 1969; 10) Card from Joe Papp; 11) Noel collage and ink by Ed Ruscha (circa 1960's); 12) "Bonne Annee 1964", $1 silver certificate mounted on paper, collage by Arman 13) Ray Johnson naked lady collage; 14) Ed Ruscha postcard drawing from Bar Harbor, ME, 1961; 15) Letter from Paulo Cesar Vacek, 1965; 16) Poem to Henry by Ben Sackheim on Beness/Lynch stationery; 17) Color xerox of a photo of Randy Hunt, 8/29/79; 18) typescript letter signed from Arthur Katz, exec VP of Jewish Theo. Sem., 19 March 1962, offering Geldzahler directorship of Jewish Museum, NYC; 19) Letter from Peter P. Smith III, 1 May 1979; 20) Envelope from Mrs. W.S. Wilson, 14 February 1963, containing four collages by Ray Johnson; 21) Letter from Shirley Woodward, 24 November 1962; 22) Letter from K.S) Rorimer, 10 May 19 ?; 23) Clipping from NY Times picturing Onassis, Taylor, Fonteyn, Geldzahler, handwritten note on top from "Robert" [Mapplethorpe]; 24) Long postcard from Martial Raysse (in French) 17 January 1963; 25) Letter and invite from Robert Irwin, 9 December 1962.1 page typescript, 2 pages autograph manuscript letter signed; 26) Envelope with Washington Post clipping, 27 May 1963, of Lucius Battle, sent by and with note from S.R. Woodward; 27) Letter from Jean Tinguely, 23 May 1962. 1 page; 28) Envelope of materials from and pertaining to Ray Johnson.16 items, 1963; 29) Copy of Suzy Stanton essay on Warhol Soup Cans; 30) 2 clippings of B&W images of John Covert paintings; 31) Program to BAM The Photographer, 4 October 1983; 32) Letter from Stan "Posty" Posthorn, 22 May 1979; 33) Photocopy of Frank Holland article on Pop Art, no date; 34) 1 page typescript letter signed from Dale Chihuly, no date; 35) Letter from George Segal, 19 March 1963; 36) George Herms collage and drawing, 1962; 37) Envelope with Jonathan Price book and slide, 14 May 1974.
  - Unsorted material, 1960-1985 (Box 12, Folder 8.4)
    1) "The City at 42nd St" re-development map/flyer foldout; 2) Photocopy of article on The NEA by Michael S. Joyce; 3) Copy of letter to K. McNally from Risa Dickstein, Esq., 26 March 1985, regarding Café Luxemborg, a restaurant Geldzahler was an investor in; 4) Queens Museum 1983 Annual cat. and press releases; 5) Letter from Phoenix Art Museum, 1984; 6) Brief piece by Henry on Jeff Vaughn's Scull Action; 7) Photocopy of Henry's letter to Paige Powell, 26 Apr. 1984; 8) Bill from photographer Andrew Moore, 20 June 1984; 9) Letter regarding tax forms from Architectural Digest, 6 November 1984; 10) Letter from Renee McKee regarding Sandak Slide library, 2 February 1983; 11) Note from Nicholas Christy, MD, 9 February 19 ?; 12) May 5, 1983 agreement regarding $25,000 loan to Geldzahler from J. Schnabel, handwritten by Henry, signed by both parties; 13) Xerox of Schnabel/Geldzahler agreement; 14) Alex Katz homemade Xmas Card, 1961; 15) Letter from Robert L. Thompson; 16) Letter from J. Armingeat, Gazette des Beaux-Arts, 24 September 1962; 17) Antique postcard in envelope from Ray Johnson, 6 June 1962; 18) Letter from Clive Miller, 10 February 1962; 19) Letter from Jean Weinbaum, Paris, 7 May 1962; 20) Soft paper greeting card from Stefan Martin; 21) Letter from Gerd Stern; 22) Handwritten birthday note in envelope from Norman Mailer, 1962; 23) Postcard from Terry (Banell?); 24) Note from Lawrence Bensky, 9 May 1962; 25) Card in envelope from Red Grooms and Mimi Gross, 1961; 26) Nolandesque postcard by Ray Johnson, May 1962; 27) Letter from Fairfield Porter, 21 August 1961, recto and verso; 28) letter from A. Barskaya, 19 September 1960, regarding Matisse drawings at Pushkin Museum; 29) Letter from Eric Sackheim, Tokyo; 30) Letter from R. Smith, London, July 1961; 31) Letter from R. Smith, London, December 1961; 32) Envelope of fragments from Ray Johnson, 13 November 1961; 33) Carbon copy of Charles Olson poem sent by Tony Weinberger; 34) Letter from "Lee," mailed from Tokyo, 1960; 35) 1984 papers regarding Barry Keldoulis; 36) Postcard 1962 from Niki de St Phalle; 37) Blank Rockwell Kent Xmas card, man leaning against post; 38) Blank Rockwell Kent Xmas card, angel lighting tree; 39) Ave Maria woodcut on Arches paper, prob Rockwell Kent.
  - Unsorted material, 1962-1988 (Box 12, Folder 8.5)
    1) 3 Posters from Geldzahler Russian exhibit "Representations of America" c. 1977; 2) Envelope of miscellaneous color slides of work by Noland, Magritte, etc; 3) 3 Larry Rivers folding cards; 4) Mailing from National Museum of Art, Osaka, 1983 regarding Christo exhibit; 5) NY Painting and Sculpture show, 1970 pamphlet; 6) Essay on Francis Bacon by Hugh M. Davies, 1974; 7) Mailing from Galerie Rive Droite, Paris, 1962 (Niki de St Phalle art work on envelope); 8) Mailing from Chelsea Gallery, NYC, 1962; 9) Lee Bontecou poster from Castelli, 1960's; 10) 2 Photos of Geldzahler and Isamu Noguchi in Venice, from Isamuya, 22 August 1986; 11) Invite to wedding of Mr. J.A. Rosenquist and Melinda McLean; 12) Invite to ADAA award dinner for Clem Greenberg; 13) Letter from David Miller, Art Investors, 13 July 1984; 14) Draft of letter from Henry to Tony Moore; 15) Letter and clippings from Miami Beach (The Strand), 12 August 1986. Restaurant Geldzahler invested in; 16) Clipping of article on Aladar Marberger (Newsday, 20 July 1986); 17) Letter from Laband (Loyola Marymount Univ.) Ellen Ekedal regarding Hockney show, 28 August 1986; 18) Letter from Paul Hunter, 28 August 1986; 19) Letter from David Crockett, 9 June 1986; 20) Letter from Stephen Jamail, 5 September 1986; 21) Letter from John Wetenhall, 15 September 1986 (Smithsonian); 22) Resume of Mark Gero and letter, 23 March 1986. Letter from Mark Gero, 14 May 1986; 23) Letter from Corcoran Gallery, 26 September 1986; 24) Copy of letter from Christopher Scott to Linda Weintraub; 25) Letter from Grant Sanger, 20 October 1986; 26) Letter from Thomas N. Armstrong III, Whitney, 30 October 1986; 27) Draft of letter by Henry to Chairman of Admissions, 10 November 1988; 28) Letter from Laird Easton (U Cal. Berkeley), 13 October 1986; 29) Copy of letter to Laird Easton from Henry (Barry Keldoulis); 30) Letter from Jeffery J. York, 4 November 1986; 31) Letter from Douglas Walla (Kent), 13 January 1988; 32) Letter to Admissions Committee regarding Brad Kelleher, 29 January 1988; 33) Letter from Brad Holden regarding Kelleher, 22 January 1988; 34) Letter from J.B. Reinhold, 21 July 1987; 35) Letters to and from Smith College regarding Maureen O'Brien, March, 1988.
  - 46 B&W 8x10 photos of Henry by various photographers - Ray Charles White, Weintraub-Budd, 60's, 70's, 80's; plus photos of artists and friends with Henry (including Chihuly, Johns, Rausch, Rivers) (Box 12, Folder 8.6)
  - One stack of approximately 150 3 ½ x 3 ½" color photos of Iran trip with F. Stella, 1962; 4 (Box 12, Folder 8.7)
  - One stack of approximately 180 3 ½ x 3 ½" color photos of Iran trip with F. Stella, 1962. Also includes some Mexican photos with Chris Scott, early 1960s, circa 1962 (Box 12, Folder 8.8)
  - Frank Stella: Three envelopes, one stack of Iran photos...B&W and color. 4 envelopes of color negatives. 1963. with Frank Stella, Ambassador and Mrs Woodward. Also Turkey and Greece with Larry Stanton and Chris Scott, early 1960s, circa 1962-1963; 5 (Box 13, Folder 8.9)
  - One fat wire bound, cardboard covered book from 1958-59. Harvard PhD. oral notes, called "Henry's security notes," approximately 300 5 x 7" index cards (Box 43, Folder 8.1)
  - One La Aurora cigar box with many early 1950s photos (Box 13, Folder 8.11)
    Includes: 1) 2 photo booth strips of Henry; 2) typewritten poem from Walter (?); 3) stack of photos; of Henry, of family, of Greece, etc. B&W and color; 4) stack of postcards from Helen Frankenthaler, Lee Bontecou, Ethel Scull; 5) stack of letters; 6) typed ½ page excerpt from Tristram Shandy; 7) 4 various membership/id cards; 8) photobooth strip of blonde haired man; 9) photobooth strip of Mark Lancaster; 10) envelope with three young man photos of Henry; 11) 5 penis photos (labeled "dick-tych" by Hockney); 12) Polaroid of Henry and David H., Henry with gang around a motorbike at Harvard; 13) invoices from Castelli Gallery for Stella "Creed" (1961) and Twombly "A Study for Epic to deSade (A Crime of Passion)" 1961.
  - Henry's paper entitled "Religion in Connecticut Law" written at Yale, 1955 (Box 13, Folder 8.12)
  - Henry's essay "Life on a Medieval Barony", 1948 (Box 13, Folder 8.13)
  - [Missing] (Box 13, Folder 8.14)
  - Silken zipper bag with prayer kit (Box 13, Folder 8.15)
  - Sketchbook with green cover, water damage, ink drawings, some with charcoal, probably Larry Stanton (Box 13, Folder 8.16)
  - Blue 8 ½ x 6 ½ Joseph Gibert notebook "Serie Superieure" containing a poem, Henry's journals from Florence, etc. 288 pages, ink, 1956 (Box 13, Folder 8.17)
  - Unsorted material, 1977-1989 (Box 13, Folder 8.18)
    1) Xerox sheet of some Artaud writings on painting; 2) Xerox of article about Henry from Times-Union, 1977; 3) Announcement of Hockney show, André Emmerich, NYC, 1988; 4) Letter from Jim McHugh, photographer, that accompanied some photos; 5) Brief handwritten note by Henry, 1979; 6) Clipping of article about Henry by Jenny Landey, 21 July 1989 in Hamptons newspaper; 7) NY Post clipping, 30 July 1984 of Henry in hot air balloon; 8) Decree from Columbia University appointing Henry as Professor Adjunct, 5 November 1984; 9) Milton Glaser designed announcement for Amnesty Exhib., 10 December 19?; 10) Brief history of "Community Arts Dev. Program" (3 pages); 11) Letter from Art Against AIDS, 30 June 1987; 12) Xerox of contact sheet of photos of Ellsworth Kelly; 13) Xeroxed papers on Ellsworth Kelly's work (19 pages); 14) June/July 1979 poets and writers newsletter; 15) Museum of Modern Art flyer for entrance to Tut exhibit; 16) Essay The Bible of Borso D'Este by Adolfo Venturi; 17) Article from Art in America by Joan K. Davidson on NEA grant with note on top to Henry from the author; 18) Ellsworth Kelly bibliography (incomplete, to 1981); 19) March 1989 issue of The Smithsonian Associate magazine; 20) Xerox of announcement of Henry's lecture, 29 March 1988 at Hirshorn.
  - Notes entitled "Parrish Lecture", green ink on legal paper. 8 pages (Box 13, Folder 8.19)
  - 11 pages of lecture notes in Geldzahler's hand, an address before the ARLIS convention at Museum of Modern Art, green ink on legal paper, 1986. Also in same folder, 5 pages lecture notes, "Art in Collaboration," High Museum, Atlanta. circa 1986 (Box 13, Folder 8.2)
  - Unsorted material, 1964-1989 (Box 13, Folder 8.21)
    1) Copy of December '89 issue of "03 Tokyo Calling" magazine including Warhol article by Geldzahler - History of Interview mag; 2) Letter from John de Christopharo; 3) Letter from Michael Abrams, 30 January 1982; 4) Postcard from "Ed" (not Ruscha), 11 March 1985; 5) Note on card, undated, from David Warren; 6) Invoice from Elite Window Treatment, 1984; 7) Postcard from curator Stephen Buckley, 1966; 8) Letter from Anthony Bufi, 17 January 1987; 9) Card and letter from Gerard Basquiat (Jean Michel's father); 10) Letter and photos from Tony Bufi,(art student) 7 November 1983; 11) Postcard from Japan from Christo, 10/86; 12) Torn piece of paper dated November 19 with note from Francesco Clemente; 13) Postcard in envelope from Peggy Biderman, 22 August 1986; 14) Charles Bell "Candy Dish" card #20/100 to Henry and Raymond, 1988; 15) Statement by Henry regarding Francesco Clemente, immigration related, dated 24 November 1982; 16) Invite to John Cage performance with David Tudor, 1964, with letter from Xenia Cage, 21 August 1964; 17) Postcard from Diego Cortez, 29 December 1987, Peru; 18) Letter with drawing from Anthony Bufi, 7 June 1987; 19) Letter from Dale Chihuly, 16 December 1985; 20) Letter from Emilio Cruz, 25 October 1984; 21) 14 April 1984 letter from Bob Colescott, U of AZ; 22) Letter of admiration from Thomas Conway, 19 June 1986; 23) 24 October 1986 letter from Sally Chamberlain, France; 24) Small packet of photos, letters, info. from Bruce Davidson starting 1981 subway project; 25) 26 March 1965 letter from Mark di Suvero; 26) 6 May 1984 letter from Eugene Draper; 27) 23 December 1987 letter with photos from Louis Allen; 28) Thank you note from William Copley (date ?) 29) Marriage invite from The Marquis of Dufferin; 30) Invoice and letter for artwork from Dan Dailey, 30 December 1985; 31) 28 March 1988 card from Bearman; 32) 21 December 1985 card from Elaine de Kooning; 33) Undated card from Sally Hazelet Drummond; 34) November 1982 Camera Arts mag with Bruce Davidson subway photo spread.
  - Correspondence, 1984-1989 (Box 13, Folder 8.22)
    1) Letter from Gregory Long in support of David Rothenberg, 11 April 1984; 2) 19 January 1984 typescript letter signed letter from Mayor Ed Koch regarding Doris Freedman, arts patron; 3) 14 March 1984 draft of letter by Henry to Admissions Committee of Century Association; 4) 28 June 1985 letter from Trudy C. Kramer/The Parrish Art Museum; 5) 2 May 1986 letter from Daniel Newburg; 6) 16 August 1986 letter from Maco Livingstone, London; 7) 26 September 1986 letter from Harrison J. Goldin, AJC; 8) 21 May 1985 letter from Alan Jones; 9) 20 June 1985 letter from Risa Dickstein regarding Café Luxemborg; 10) 24 June 1985 letter from Candy Coleman regarding Massimo Audiello; 11) 16 May 1985 letter from Denver Art Museum; 12) 29 March 1985 letter from Carol Henry, ICCA; 13) Xerox copy of "Art At The Palladium" article by Alan Jones; 14) 12 May 1985 letter from Elle magazine; 15) Letter from John Reinhold, 24 May 1985; 16) 25 January 1985 form letter from Gorewitz, Duque and Co; 17) 25 January 1985 letter from Michael Zellman, American Art Analog; 18) Letters from and to David MacEachron, August 1984; 19) 11 May 1984 letter from Richard Hertz; 20) 2 January 1985 letter from Ileen Shepperd, Queens Museum; 21) July 1984 letter from Stephen Benedict, Columbia University; 22) Packet of letters and drafts regarding Dewars Profile ad with Henry, 1989-90; 23) Envelope with 31 January 1984 letter from Diego Cortez regarding bounced checks; 24) Letter from Blum-Helman, 14 November 1985; 25) 2 September 1985 letter from Keith McNally, Café Luxemborg; 26) 5 April 1984 letter from Joan Jeffri, Columbia University; 27) 24 March 1984 letter from Joan Jeffri, Columbia University; 28) 28 February 1984 letter from Stephen Benedict, Columbia University; 29) Columbia U. Arts Administration syllabus, Spring 1984. A class taught by Geldzahler on arts administration; 30) 13 August 1984 letter from Catherine Keen, Archives of Amer. Art; 31) 5 November 1984 letter from Richard G. Perry, Brooklyn Bridge; 32) Certificate of appreciation from 1983 Brooklyn Bridge Centennial; 33) 29 November 1984 letter from Oni Berglund, Collectors Forum; 34) 4 March 1985 letter from Mildred Andrews fund; 35) 5 February 1985 letter from Danielle Rice, National Gallery; 36) Draft of letter to Mrs. Carol Stone, 11 September 1984; 37) 28 May 1985 letter from Stephen Benedict, Columbia University; 38) Xerox of letter to Streator Corp. (on Henry's behalf) from Dickstein and Fabricant, attorneys regarding Café Luxemborg; 39) 5 June 1985 letter from Joseph Hintersteiner, Arts Interaction; 40) 7 January 1985 letter from Evelyn Aronson, Museum Contempage Art, Chicago; 41) 27 September 1985 letter from Stuart E. Jacobson, Only The Best; 42) 21 June 1985 letter from Museo de Arte Costarricense regarding Chia; 43) Letter by Henry to Howard Conant, 11 October 1985; 44) 13 September 1985 letter from Howard Conant; 45) Curriculum Vitae for Robert Colescott; 46) Letter and statement concerning artwork of Larry Stanton; 47) Permission form from Pantheon Books, 25 November 1985; 48) Copy of Yale application of Michael Rauch, and Henry's letter of recommendation; 49) Letter for Steve Reinhold, 7 February 1985; 50) 6 March 1986 letter from Janis Ekdahl, Museum of Modern Art; 51) 27 March 1986 letter from Ima Ebong, Brown Univ; 52) 13 March 1986 letter from Toni Petersen, ARLIS NA 53) 29 May 1986 letter from John A. DeGrace, Nassau County; 54) 8 April 1985 letter from Walter A. Arensberg; 55) 12 November 1985 letter from Ima Ebong, Brown Univ; 56) 9 April 1984 letter from John McGuire, landlord for Southampton; 57) 18 December 1985 letter and clippings from Frank Perry; 58) Empty envelope from Yale Univ. registrar, 20 November 1985; 59) 2 April 1988 announcement from Robert Rygor; 60) Letter from Guggenheim Foundation, 1969 and with statement from candidate Omar Rayo (relief prints); 61) 13 June 1989 letter from Robert Littman, CCAC Mexico.
  - Folder of prints, slides and transparencies and other materials concerning DIA show of Enrique Castro-Cid (Box 13, Folder 8.23)
  - Unsorted material (Box 13, Folder 8.24)
    1) Envelope with photos of Chuck Hinman piece, 1964; 2) Listing of Vowel Paintings of Francesco Clemente, DIA 1989; 3) Brief note from Connie to Hollis on Leo Castelli stationery; 4) Olympia SFL typewriter manual; 5) Henry's lease with John C. McGuire for 33 West 9th St., NYC, 1980-1982; 6) Henry's lease for 33 W9, 1985; 7) Financial memo from Arthur Lambert, April 1985 regarding 33 West 9th St.
  - Unsorted material, 1953-1989 (Box 14, Folder 8.25)
    1) Typescript for Henry's lecture, 22 February 1984 at Phoenix Art Museum, "European Sources for American Art, "typed with extensive hand corrections by Geldzahler, 22 pages; 2) Transcript of 17 August 1983 lecturer on "Public Spaces" by Henry at Copley Square Centennial Committee, 26 pages. Corrections by Geldzahler in pencil; 3) Script for Geldzahler lecture, Friends of Art, Lowe Art Museum, 9 February 1983, 30 pages; 4) Geldzahler lecture at The Whitney, "Cross-Pollination: European and American Art" (circa 1985), 27 pages; 5) Handwritten, ink on legal pad, notes for Henry's lecture "Make It New" at Smithsonian /Hirshhorn, 29 March 1989, 18 pages; 6) Essay: "FAUVISM" by Henry Geldzahler, carbon copy typescript, 63 pages and footnotes, written approximately 1956; 7) Henry's High School Diploma, 1953, Horace Mann, including a newspaper clipping of Henry with youthful goatee.
  - Envelope marked "Horace Mann and Massad" containing 33 items: high school correspondence, school essays, grade reports, one summer camp group photo (Box 14, Folder 8.26)
  - Typescript and autograph manuscript, 3 page essay entitled "Visual Arts in the 1970's" (Box 14, Folder 8.27)
  - Six audiocassettes, 1983-1988 (Box 14, Folder 8.28)